<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<report>
<checksum>report105</checksum>
<subtype>PALLIATIVE CONSULT</subtype>
<type>HP</type>
<chief_complaint />
<admit_diagnosis />
<discharge_diagnosis />
<year>2007</year>
<downlaod_time>2009-10-05</downlaod_time>
<update_time />
<deid>v.6.22.08.0</deid>
<report_text>[Report de-identified (Safe-harbor compliant) by De-ID v.6.22.08.0]


 
**INSTITUTION
PALLIATIVE CARE
CONSULTATION
 
PATIENT NAME:  **NAME[AAA, BBB M]
ACCOUNT #:  **ID-NUM
**ROOM
ATTENDING PHYSICIAN:  **NAME[UUU]  **NAME[VVV]
CONSULTING PHYSICIAN:  **NAME[UUU]  **NAME[VVV]
DATE OF ADMISSION:  **DATE[Aug 25 2006]
DATE OF CONSULTATION:  **DATE[Aug 25 06]  
 
 
REASON FOR CONSULT: 
 
1. Discussion of goals.
2. Symptoms.
 
Ms. **NAME[AAA] is a **AGE[in 70s]-year-old woman who was admitted to **INSTITUTION on **DATE[Aug 25]
 for some change in mental status, confusion, and agitation.  She had recently
 been put on _____.  A condition C was called because the patient was found
 down in a pool of vomit.  A CT of the head showed an acute right
 frontoparietal parenchymal bleed with intravascular extension and mild right
 to left subuncal  herniation.   
 
The patient was brought to the unit, sedated with propofol, and put on the
 ventilator.  Her initial blood pressure 
Was 210.  Since she has been in the unit, she has remained comfortable.
 
I talked to the patient's husband, sister, son, granddaughter, and niece for a
 total of 70 minutes.  Greater than 60% of that was face-to-face time with the
 patient and family.  
 
The patient has a history of hypertension.  
 
Social history:  She lives with her husband and has the family as stated
 above.  No alcohol, drugs, or tobacco.
 
Family history:  Unremarkable.
 
Review of systems:  Review of systems at the current time is unobtainable from
 the patient; however, the family thinks the patient is comfortable.  
 
 
 
 
PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  
 
1. Coronary artery disease/CABG.
2. CNS aneurysm.
3. Dementia.
 
PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:
 
The patient is sedate, not responsive to my voice.  She is stable on the
 ventilator. 
 
Vital signs:  Stable and in no acute distress.
 
Chest:  Clear breath sounds anteriorly.
 
Abdomen:  Nontender.
 
Extremities:  No edema.
 
LABORATORY TESTS:  
 
CT as per above. Chest x-ray shows some mild pulmonary edema.  CT of the head
 from **DATE[Aug 18] shows there are some  chronic changes and old cerebellar
 hemorrhages.  BUN and creatinine 11 and 0.8.  Calcium 7.6, albumin in **DATE[Apr]
 was 4.3.  LFTs in **DATE[Apr] were within normal limits.  Hematocrit is 42.
 
ASSESSMENT:  The patient is a **AGE[in 70s]-year-old woman who suffered a major stroke.
  
 
PLAN:  
 
1. At the current time, the patient remains comfortable.  I have no further
 symptom recs.  
2. If shortness of breath becomes an issue, I would use opiates, for example,
 morphine 2 mg q. 2 hours p.r.n. 
3. If delirious, would use Haldol 1 to 2 mg IV q. 1 hours p.r.n..
 
GOALS:  The major amount of time was spent talking to the family about goals.
 I did discuss with them how this is an acute infarct, and we are not entirely
 sure how this will play out.  However, given that this was a large infarct
 with herniation, it is very serious. I tried to stress to them that
 regardless of what happens, we would keep their loved one comfortable and to
 the best we can to maximize her care.  I did, however, try to prepare them to
 the fact that this was a severe stroke that the patient may not recover from.
   The family certainly seemed to understand.  They are waiting to hear from
 neurosurgery to hear if there are any other options or to hear what their
 opinion is.  At the current time, they stressed no needs, but they were going
 to talk together as a family.  
 
 
___________________________________
**NAME[WWW M. XXX], M.D.
 
 
 
Dictator:  **NAME[WWW M. XXX], M.D.
 
**INITIALS
 
D:  **DATE[Aug 25 2006] 16:47:41
T:  **DATE[Aug 26 2006] 04:59:45
R:  **DATE[Aug 26 2006] 04:59:45/msz
 
Job ID:  110530/**ID-NUM
 
Cc:
 
 
 
 
*** Dictated By: -**NAME[XXX, TTT M]. ***
Electronically Signed by **NAME[WWW XXX]  **DATE[Sep 14 2006] 07:39:42 AM
 



</report_text>
</report>