<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<report>
<checksum>report74</checksum>
<subtype>PALLIATIVE CONSULT</subtype>
<type>HP</type>
<chief_complaint />
<admit_diagnosis />
<discharge_diagnosis />
<year>2007</year>
<downlaod_time>2009-10-05</downlaod_time>
<update_time />
<deid>v.6.22.08.0</deid>
<report_text>[Report de-identified (Safe-harbor compliant) by De-ID v.6.22.08.0]


 
**INSTITUTION
PALLIATIVE CARE
CONSULTATION
PATIENT NAME:  **NAME[AAA, BBB M]
ACCOUNT #:  **ID-NUM
**ROOM
ATTENDING PHYSICIAN:  **NAME[YYY XXX ZZZ]
CONSULTING PHYSICIAN:  **NAME[YYY XXX ZZZ]
DATE OF ADMISSION:  **DATE[Jun 02 2006]
DATE OF CONSULTATION:  **DATE[Jul 02 06]  
HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS: 
Briefly, the patient is a **AGE[in 70s]-year-old woman with the past medical history
 significant for coronary artery disease, CABG times two, AVR, aortic root
 aneurysm, infrarenal aneurysm, and a thoracoabdominal aneurysm with
 dissection.  
Her care was then complicated by thrombocytopenia following heparin while in
 the OR, believed to be HIT, difficulty weaning from the ventilator and
 tracheostomy, MRSA, left bilateral lower leg weakness postop which has been
 more on the left recently than the right, bilateral subdural hematomas and
 most recently left lung collapse with repetitive bronchoscopies.  
The patient also has had a 3B cervical cancer for which she just finished
 radiation therapy.  
We were asked to see the patient for depression and pain.
On talking to her, she says that she does not have any pain.  She has some
 mild shortness of breath.  She also notes some fatigue and sadness.  She was
 started on antidepressants roughly two weeks ago at 20 mg of Celexa.  It is
 hard to talk to her because she is intubated, so it is hard to tell whether
 this has improved or not.  The nurse's feel that it has not and that is quite
 teary all the time.  
PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  
Past medical history is as noted in the chart.  
MEDICATIONS:   
Medications are as noted in the chart.
 
SOCIAL HISTORY: 
The patient has a living will, and the primary attending talked to the family,
 and the decision was that it would be okay to do short-term ventilation and
 to do simply things like colostomy but not take her back to the operating
 room.
The patient is a Christian.  
____________ Symptom Assessment Scale is positive only for the fatigue,
 shortness of breath, and the feelings of sadness.  She just had a
 bronchoscopy and Versed, so she is still relatively fatigued.  
FUNCTIONAL STATUS:  The patient is blind in her left eye.  She is quite hard
 of hearing.  She is dependent on all ADLs through this acute hospitalization.
  
PAIN:  The patient had a Duragesic patch, so it was taken off today when she
 dropped her hemoglobin.
FAMILY HISTORY: 
Family history is unobtainable.  
PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:   
GENERAL APPEARANCE:  The patient is a somnolent female who awakens and can
 follow simple commands.  She is quite hard of hearing.  She is wearing
 glasses.  
HEENT:  Pupils are equally reactive to light.  She has a tracheostomy.  Mouth
 is grossly normal.  
CHEST:  Lungs:  Decreased breath sounds on the left.  Regular rate and rhythm.
  She has JVD at the clavicle.  She has no S3 or S4.  
ABDOMEN:  The abdomen is soft and nontender.  She is slightly distended.  She
 has a G-tube.  
EXTREMITIES:  She has some cyanosis and coldness of her left foot.  She does
 have pulses.  
NEUROLOGIC:  Neurologically, she is grossly nonfocal.  I cannot rule out
 extensive motor examination.  
LABORATORY, RADIOGRAPHIC, AND OTHER DIAGNOSTIC STUDY FINDINGS:   
Her laboratory data was reviewed.  Her hemoglobin has markedly decreased.
ASSESSMENT AND PLAN:   
1. Pain.  I stopped the Duragesic patch because she was hypotensive.  Will
 leave the p.r.n. medicine as the patient is not having any pain at this time
 and will follow.  
2. High risk for decubitus.  Does not have any decubitus at this time.  Will
 need to watch carefully.  
3. Depression.  As the patient is already on Celexa, increase to 40 a day.
 Will try to evaluate more fully when she is more awake.
4. Goals.  The patient has a living will.  The primary team is in talking to
 the Durable Power of Attorney, so we will follow at a distance.
___________________________________
**NAME[VVV M. WWW], M.D.
Dictator:  **NAME[VVV M. WWW], M.D.
**INITIALS
D:  **DATE[Jul 02 2006] 17:52:03
T:  **DATE[Jul 05 2006] 22:34:17
R:  **DATE[Jul 05 2006] 22:34:17/plb
Job ID:  41358/**ID-NUM
*** Dictated By: -**NAME[TTT] ***
Electronically Signed by **NAME[VVV WWW]  **DATE[Jul 06 2006] 09:02:04 AM
 



</report_text>
</report>