<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<report>
<checksum>report45</checksum>
<subtype>CONSULT</subtype>
<type>HP</type>
<chief_complaint>CHEST PAIN</chief_complaint>
<admit_diagnosis>786.50</admit_diagnosis>
<discharge_diagnosis>786.59,592.1,599.0,496,041.04,414.01,250.00,272.4,300.4,V12.59,V43.65,729.1,</discharge_diagnosis>
<year>2007</year>
<downlaod_time>2009-08-18</downlaod_time>
<update_time />
<deid>v.6.22.07.0</deid>
<report_text>[Report de-identified (Safe-harbor compliant) by De-ID v.6.22.07.0]


The patient was seen and examined, and the chart was reviewed.  

CHIEF COMPLAINT/HISTORY OF PRESENT ILLNESS:  The patient is a **AGE[in 50s]-year-old 
whit female well known to our service with multiple **INSTITUTION 
admissions for chest pain.  She has diabetes, hypertension, and 
hyperlipidemia.  She has known coronary artery disease with pervious 
intracoronary stenting.  The patient states that yesterday, while sitting in 
home, she has stabling midsternal chest discomfort associated with some 
shortness of breath.  She has stable dyspnea on exertion.  No PND, orthopnea, 
or increased lower extremity edema, palpitations, or lightheadedness.  The 
patient was brought to the emergency room.  She was given two sublingual 
nitroglycerin.  She said there was some relief of the pain, but morphine is 
what took the pain away.  She had another episode last night which responded 
to Vicodin.  She is currently, resting comfortably, sitting in a chair 
without complaints.

PAST MEDICAL HISTORY:  
1.  Coronary artery disease, previous intracoronary stents.
2.  Diabetes mellitus.
3.  Hypertension.
4.  Hyperlipidemia.

CURRENT MEDICATIONS:  Please see nursing assessment sheet which I have 
reviewed.

ALLERGIES:  No known drug allergies.

SOCIAL HISTORY:  Negative for tobacco and alcohol.

FAMILY HISTORY:  Noncontributory.

REVIEW OF SYSTEMS:  No significant recent weight loss or weight gain or 
change in bowel or bladder habits.  No fevers, chills, cough, nausea, 
vomiting, or headache.  Chest pain as above, shortness of breath, PND, 
orthopnea, or palpitations.  She has chronic mild lower extremity edema.  No 
palpitations or lightheadedness.  No change in vision or hearing acuity.  No 
difficulty with speech.  No focal numbness, weakness, or tingling of the 
extremities.  No symptoms of depression.  No musculoskeletal aches or pains.  
All other systems are negative.

PHYSICAL EXAMINATION:  GENERAL APPEARANCE:  This is a pleasant obese 
middle-aged  female in no acute distress.
VITAL SIGNS:  Stable.  She is afebrile.
HEENT:  Head is atraumatic and normocephalic.  Eyes:  Pupils equal, round, 
and reactive to light and accommodation.  Extraocular movements are intact.  
Sclerae are white, conjunctivae pink.  Oral mucosa is moist.  No lesions or 
exudates.
NECK:  No JVD.  Carotids 2+.  No bruit or lymphadenopathy.
CHEST:  Clear lung fields to auscultation and percussion bilaterally.
CARDIAC:  Precordium is quiet.  PMI nondisplaced.  Regular rate and rhythm.  
S1, S2.  No murmurs, gallops, or rubs.  
ABDOMEN:  Soft, nontender.  Positive bowel sounds.  No hepatosplenomegaly.  
No masses or bruits.
EXTREMITIES:  No clubbing, cyanosis, or edema.  Peripheral pulses are full.  
Edema 2+ bilaterally.    
NEUROLOGIC:  She is alert and oriented to time.  No focal neurological 
deficits.

LABORATORY DATA:  Admission laboratories were reviewed.

IMPRESSION:  The patient was admitted with chest pain was clinically atypical 
for angina pectoris.  The patient has had multiple previous **INSTITUTION admissions for similar complaints of chest pain which usually 
responds to narcotics rather than nitrates.  The patient however, does have 
multiple cardiac risk factors including diabetes, and she has known coronary 
artery disease with previous intracoronary stents.  Her last stress test was 
3 years ago.  Because of her multiple risk factors despite atypical nature of 
the pain, her normal EKG and negative enzymes we will proceed with a stress 
test today.  If this is negative, the patient will be discharged home.  Her 
blood pressure is adequately controlled, and she is on a statin for 
dyslipidemia.

Thanks for this consultation.


______________________________
**NAME[WWW M. XXX], M.D.

HS Job # 926600 / 39810 / 
# **ID-NUM
D: **DATE[Apr 24 2007] 12:31
T: **DATE[Apr 25 2007] 02:52




</report_text>
</report>