<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<report>
<checksum>report112</checksum>
<subtype>NEUROSURG OP</subtype>
<type>OP</type>
<chief_complaint>TRIGEMINAL NEURALGIA</chief_complaint>
<admit_diagnosis>350.1</admit_diagnosis>
<discharge_diagnosis>350.1,V10.3,401.9,733.00,272.0,426.3,785.2,</discharge_diagnosis>
<year>2007</year>
<downlaod_time>2009-10-05</downlaod_time>
<update_time />
<deid>v.6.22.08.0</deid>
<report_text>[Report de-identified (Safe-harbor compliant) by De-ID v.6.22.08.0]


 
**INSTITUTION
NEUROSURGERY
OPERATIVE REPORT
PATIENT NAME:  **NAME[AAA, BBB M]
ACCOUNT #:  **ID-NUM
**ROOM
SURGEON:  **NAME[VVV M. WWW], M.D.
ASSISTANT(S):  
ATTENDING PHYSICIAN:  **NAME[YYY XXX ZZZ]
SURGERY DATE:  **DATE[Sep 03 06]
ADMISSION DATE:  **DATE[Sep 03 2007]
DISCHARGE DATE:  
PREOPERATIVE DIAGNOSIS:  LEFT TRIGEMINAL NEURALGIA.
POSTOPERATIVE DIAGNOSIS:  LEFT TRIGEMINAL NEURALGIA.
PROCEDURE:  LEFT RETROMASTOID CRANIOTOMY; MICROVASCULAR DECOMPRESSION LEFT 
FIFTH NERVE; BOVINE DURAPLASTY; TITANIUM PLATE CRANIOPLASTY. 
STAFF:  **NAME[VVV M. WWW], M.D., and Dr. **NAME[ZZZ].
RESIDENT:  **NAME[VVV UUU], M.D.
ANESTHESIA:  General endotracheal anesthesia.
COMPLICATIONS:  None.
SPECIMENS:  None.
INTRAOPERATIVE MONITORING:  Brainstem auditory evoked responses with 
somatosensory evoked potentials. 
INDICATIONS FOR OPERATION:  The patient is a **AGE[in 60s]-year-old woman with typical 
trigeminal neuralgia.  The patient has opted for microvascular decompression. 
 Options for less invasive therapies including radiosurgery and percutaneous 
procedures risks were discussed.  Consent was given.  Risks of stroke, death, 
failure, hearing loss, facial paralysis, facial numbness, double vision, 
infection, and spinal fluid leak were discussed. 
DESCRIPTION OF OPERATION:  The patient was identified and brought to the 
operating room.  She was placed under general anesthesia.  Her head was put 
in the Mayfield-Kees headholder, and she was put in the lateral decubitus 
position with her left side up.  All pressures points were padded, and she 
was taped to the table.  Neurophysiological monitoring lines were placed.  
The left retromastoid region was shaved, prepped, and draped in the usual 
sterile fashion.  A 5-cm linear incision was made just behind the hairline.  
Self-retaining retractors were placed, and a subperiosteal dissection was 
carried out.  **NAME[TTT SSS] drill was used to perform retromastoid craniotomy 
such that the edges of the transverse and sigmoid sinuses were exposed.  Air 
cells were waxed, and the wound was copiously irrigated with antibiotic 
saline.  The dura was now opened in a curvilineal fashion and reflected 
laterally using four Nurolon tack-up sutures.  The microscope was brought in. 
Using microsurgical dissection techniques, the eleventh nerve cistern was 
identified.  The arachnoid was opened and CSF came forth.  The cerebellum 
relaxed well.  The arachnoid over the fifth nerve was not dissected free.  
The petrosal vein was cauterized and divided.  The fifth nerve was well 
visualized.  A large vein compressing the fifth nerve was decompressed with 
Teflon pledgets.  A small artery at the reentry zone was also decompressed 
with Teflon pledgets.   Having completed the decompression, we turned our 
attention to closing.  A duraplasty was carried out with bovine pericardium, 
as the dura could not be closed primarily.  The air cells were re-waxed.  The 
wound was copiously irrigated with antibiotic saline.  A titanium plate 
cranioplasty was performed.  The muscle and fascial layers were closed with 
interrupted inverted 2-0 and 3-0 Vicryl suture, the skin was closed with 
running 4-0 Ethilon stitch.  Sterile dressings were applied.  The patient was 
ultimately removed from the Mayfield-Kees headholder, extubated, and 
transferred to the recovery room in stable condition. 
ATTESTATION STATEMENT:  Please note Dr. **NAME[ZZZ] and **NAME[M] were present and 
scrubbed for this procedure and performed the entire procedure with the 
assistance of Dr. **NAME[UUU]. 
______________________________________
**NAME[VVV M. WWW], M.D.
 
Dictator:  **NAME[VVV M. WWW], M.D.
**INITIALS
D:  **DATE[Sep 03 2007] 17:36:50
T:  **DATE[Sep 04 2007] 10:42:43
R:  **DATE[Sep 04 2007] 10:42:43/rk
Job ID:  331031/**ID-NUM
Cc:
 
*** Dictated By: -**NAME[WWW, RRR M]. ***
Electronically Signed by **NAME[VVV WWW]  **DATE[Sep 10 2007] 05:36:56 PM
 



</report_text>
</report>